Jacome's Department Store records, 1901-1980
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series 6: Alianza Hispano-Americana; 1913-1947, About 250 items (.4 linear feet)
  - Correspondence. 1936-1940 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Financial Statements. 1913-1947 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous. 1901-1980 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Publications. 1914-1942 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Series 7: Photographs; 1922-1966, About 250 items (.4 linear feet)
  The Photographs series contains dated and undated photographs including images of the Stone and Pennington store while under construction, festivities surrounding the grand opening of the Stone and Pennington store in 1951 (interior and exterior), the unveiling of the Jacome's 58th anniversary logo, and miscellaneous store window displays. Also included are miscellaneous photographs of Alex G. Jacome dining with Mexican government officials as well as picture postcards of family members. [Note: Additional photographs are found in Series 10: Oversized Materials].
  - Miscellaneous. 1901-1980 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous. 1922-1966 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Series 8: Real Estate; 1901-1980, About 2,500 items (3.5 linear feet)
  The Real Estate series contains insurance policy information; legal documents including abstracts of title, contracts, deeds, leases, mortgages, and zoning provisions; and plans and blueprints for new stores and the expansion of existing stores. [Note: Additional building plans are located in Series 10: Oversized Material].
  - Insurance; Policy Information. 1951-1954 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Legal; Abstract of Title. 1907 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Legal; Abstract of Title. 1909 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Legal; Abstract of Title. 1914 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Legal; Abstract of Title. 1930 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Legal; Abstract of Title. 1931 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Legal; Abstract of Title. 1934 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Legal; Abstract of Title. 1938 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Legal; Abstract of Title. 1941 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Legal; Certificate of Title. 1905 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Legal; Contract for the Construction of a Residence and Garage. 1937 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Legal; Contract for Remodeling of Department Store. undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Legal; Contracts for the Sale of Real Estate. 1938-1948 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Legal; Deeds. 1901-1980 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Legal; Deeds. 1901-1913 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Legal; Deeds. 1920-1934 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Legal; Deeds. 1944-1945 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Legal; Escrow. 1926 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Legal; Leases. 1901-1980 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Legal; Leases. 1937 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Legal; Leases. 1938-1939 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Legal; Leases. 1940 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Legal; Leases. 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Legal; Leases. 1942 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Legal; Leases. 1945 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Legal; Leases. 1946 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Legal; Leases. 1947 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Legal; Miscellaneous. 1901-1980 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Legal; Miscellaneous. 1903-1931 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Legal; Mortgages. 1904-1914 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Legal; Mortgages. 1921-1930 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Legal; Mortgages. 1937-1946 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Legal; Mortgages. 1940-1945 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Legal; Zoning Provisions. 1901-1980 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Arizona Bank Plaza. 1975 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Arizona Building Company. 1955 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Custom Built Fixtures. 1957 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Coronado Village. 1977 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Plans and Blueprints; El Capri Shoppes. 1976 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Jacome's Alterations. 1964 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Jacome's Expansion. 1956 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Jacome's Gift Department. 1963 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Jacome's Men's Shop. 1967 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Jacome's Pennington & Stone Store (1 of 2). 1956 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Jacome's Pennington & Stone Store (2 of 2). 1956 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Jacome's Renovation. 1975 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Jacome's Sierra Vista. 1976 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Jacome's Sierra Vista. 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Plans and Blueprints; La Placita Village. 1978 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Park and Mill Street Building. 1901-1980 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Sierra Vista Ventures. 1901-1980 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Store Additions and Alterations by Architect Terry Atkinson. 1956 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Store Equipment (1 of 2). 1950 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Store Equipment (2 of 2). 1950 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Store Furnishings. 1901-1980 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Store Layout. 1901-1980 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Plans and Blueprints; Survey Map. 1980 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Series 9: Scrapbooks; 1950-1967, About 1,000 items (1.5 linear feet)
  The Scrapbook series contains a scrapbook highlighting the activities of the Jacome's Hi Board High School Fashion Club; two scrapbooks contemporaneous with the building of the new store at Stone and Pennington Streets in 1951, and a historical overview of the store at Stone and Pennington put together in 1967. The scrapbooks include photographs, news clippings, radio scripts, advertisements, and a few 35mm slides.
  - Jacome's Hi Board. 1961-1967 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - New Store. 1950-1951 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - The Story of Jacome's Modern Store at Stone and Pennington. 1950-1951 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - The Story of Jacome's Modern Store at Stone and Pennington. 1967 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Series 10: Oversized Materials; 1939-1979, About 3,000 items (4.5 linear feet)
  The Oversized Materials series contains items from other series that are too large to fit in standard record cartons. Items include a payroll ledger covering the years 1939-1950, advertising artwork, and several large photographs. The photographs include an undated poster-sized print of an aerial view of downtown Tucson, undated poster-prints of the exteriors and interiors of La Bonanza General Store and Jacome's Department Store, an undated poster-sized print of the Park Brewery in Tucson, and several large inscribed photographs of Mexican governmental officials given to Alex G. Jacome between the years 1955-1979.
  - Accounting and Finance; Payroll. 1939-1950 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Company History; Sales, Marketing, and Advertising Artwork. 1901-1980 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Company History; Sales, Marketing, and Advertising Artwork. 1951-1963 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Company History; Sales, Marketing, and Advertising Breakdown. 1960-1969 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Photographs; Aerial View of Downtown Tucson. 1901-1980 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Photographs; Inscribed (1 of 2). 1955 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Photographs; Inscribed (2 of 2). 1955 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Photographs; Inscribed. 1956 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Photographs; Inscribed. 1963 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Photographs; Inscribed. 1968 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Photographs; Inscribed. 1975 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Photographs; Inscribed. 1979 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Photographs: Jacome's Exterior. 1901-1980 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Photographs; Jacomes and Governor Obregon (Mexico). 1901-1980 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Photographs; Jacome's Interior. 1901-1980 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Photographs; La Bonanza Exterior. 1901-1980 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Photographs; La Bonanza Interior. 1901-1980 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Photographs; Park Brewery. 1901-1980 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Real Estate; Existing and Proposed Plans. 1901-1980 (Box 17, Folder 15)